<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on </title>
    <link>//www.herdagdelen.com/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.154.3</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//www.herdagdelen.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pregnancy Timeline Trends</title>
      <link>//www.herdagdelen.com/notes/pregnancy-timeline-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.herdagdelen.com/notes/pregnancy-timeline-trends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live demo:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://pregnancy.herdagdelen.com&#34;&gt;pregnancy.herdagdelen.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a project that has been on my mind for 14 years, ever since we were expecting our first child in 2012. The idea is to create an interactive tool that allows us to explore what topics expectant parents discuss over the course of a pregnancy. I wanted to see how the emotions, concerns, information needs, and experiences of expecting parents evolve from conception to birth and into the early months of parenthood. The underlying data comes from public pregnancy discussion forums where posts are organized by gestational week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of zodiac signs on LLM response diversity</title>
      <link>//www.herdagdelen.com/notes/persona-prompts-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.herdagdelen.com/notes/persona-prompts-diversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Large language models tend to collapse into a narrow set of predictable outputs when prompted multiple times with the same question &amp;ndash; a phenomenon known as &lt;em&gt;mode collapse&lt;/em&gt;. This matters for applications like brainstorming and creative writing where we want to sample a range of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this note, I share results from a kitchen-table experiment: I prompted Claude models with different zodiac signs and Myers-Briggs personality types to see if persona prompts could increase output diversity. My hypothesis is that these persona types are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
